# **Peter Bishop**

720-272-5223 ~ pjb.den@gmail.com ~ https://github.com/Pierre81385 https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-bishop-46a51597/ CUNY Baruch College ~ DU Full-Stack Bootcamp

### **PROFILE**

Full stack web developer with combined experience in the service industry and tech startups providing a balanced background of skills both customer facing and technical. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of Denver Coding Bootcamp, and a Bachelors in Business Administration from the City University of New York at Baruch college with an emphasis on Economics. Strengths in client interaction, team collaboration, and a passion for backend development.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, SWIFT

**Applications**: GitHub, MySQL, Xcode, Robo3T, MongoDB Atlas, Heroku, Salesforce, GraphQL

**Tools:** Express, Node.js, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, React, RESTful API's, JWT

#### **PROJECTS**

**Favorite Recipes**, Role: Backend developer, responsible for developing routes, creating backend to front end connections.

- https://github.com/Pierre81385/adoptADog
- https://beautiful-haleakala-80520.herokuapp.com/

Summary - A project developing a full stack web application featuring JWT auth to allow logged in users to view, like, and choose dogs available for adoption.

Tools - JWT, React, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, Bootstrap

### Weather Dashboard, Role: Sole developer

- https://github.com/TJCourey/beerMe-international
- https://tjcourey.github.io/beerMe-international/

Summary - A collaborative web app allowing users to find beers based on ABV and IBU preference, and discover details about the beer and a random translation of how to order it.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Punk and Funtranslations API's

### **EXPERIENCE**

General Manager, Sushi-Rama, Denver, CO - June 2019 to August 2020 As the General Manager, responsibilities included overseeing all aspects of restaurant operations including but not limited to staffing, BOH and FOH ordering and inventory, balancing daily and weekly checkouts, entering invoices, and conducting payroll.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Steadily increased year-over-year sales, and tracked this progress by developing a
  portfolio of spreadsheets to track and manage profit and loss, weekly inventory, cost
  of goods sold, product mix, and sales by guest count.
- Took charge of the basic administration of the company's web presence. Customizing sites for Sushi-rama, Osaka Ramen, and The Empire lounge. Developing signage, updating menus, and creating custom QR codes to adapt to the pandemic.
- Designed specialty cocktails and worked with the kitchen manager to design cost effective offerings to drive sales, clear inventory, and drive awareness of the restaurant and it's products.
- Obtained the ServSafe Manager certification.

Bartender, Mile High Spirits, Denver, CO - July 2015 to June 2019
As a bartender at MHS, I served in a high volume environment, developing positive customer relationships, ensuring customers were responsibly served and received consistent craft cocktails.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Additionally worked in production canning, bottling, and responsible for making the Denver Dry Gin.
- Lead the distillery tour program, educating guests, explaining the distillation process, and leading guided tastings.
- Obtained TIPS and Merchant Guard licenses.

QA Analyst, Data Connect Corp, Denver, CO - July 2012 to February 2018
As a QA Analyst, I tested software release features on iOS, Windows, and cloud based systems relating to an event management product. Working with JIRA for case management. Ran all database scripts on client databases to move them from testing to show ready.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Assisted with staff and equipment logistics, hiring just-in-time staff, developing hardware inventory systems, and conducting regular training to improve staff skills.
- Traveled regularly to events as a Team Leader, overseeing hardware and software deployment, executing over \$655,000 in show day services across more than 30 events per year. Provided live demos and training on our software and services to groups as large as 300, and custom reports on demand with SQL database queries to compile event statistics.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Denver, Full Stack Web Development Certificate, 2021 City University of New York, Baruch College BBA in Economics